<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Home</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Economy of Digital Capitalism</title>
      <link>/projects/political-economy-of-digital-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/political-economy-of-digital-capitalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in times where hardly a day goes by without some digital company making headlines for revolutionizing yet another aspect of our economic and social lives. These changes often have a peculiar double-dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-double-dynamic-of-digitalization&#34;&gt;The double-dynamic of digitalization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, they have a commodifying thrust, pushing economic logics ever deeper into the social fabric. Work is reorganized on digital platforms in ways that undermine existing (labor) regulations; individuals are nudged to disclose previously personal information such as health choices or reading habits as privacy increasingly comes at a cost; and new markets are created that subtly introduce opportunity cost considerations into people’s daily lives (do I lose money if I don’t sublet my spare room on Airbnb?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, they have a disruptive thrust, radically altering the requirements for success, on the individual-, firm-, and national level. Relatively rapidly, skills become obsolete, markets disappear, competitive advantages vanish, and entirely new physical and social infrastructures become increasingly essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;varieties-of-digitalization&#34;&gt;Varieties of Digitalization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The double-dynamic of digitalization confront policymakers with a whole range of challenges, from regulating platform companies, to protecting personal data, to responding to new skill and infrastructure demands. Importantly, policymakers often react very differently to these challenges, and these reactions change the nature of digitalization itself. This variance in policy responses and policy effects creates an El Dorado for social scientists trying to understand why and how digitalization varies, but also why and how capitalist societies differ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, the different trajectories digitalization takes in response to country-specific restrictions and affordances make a big difference in people´s economic, political and social lives. Consequently, technological change is not social destiny but depends on political choices (or non-choices) that can, in principle, be explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, different reactions to similar challenges reveal something about the the political entities that make them. As the comparativist Peter Gourevitch once remarked: &amp;ldquo;For social scientists who enjoy comparisons, happiness is finding a force or event which affects a number of societies at the same time. Like test-tube solutions that respond differently to the same reagent, these societies reveal their characters in divergent responses to the same stimulus” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-comparative-political-economy-of-digital-capitalism&#34;&gt;The comparative political economy of digital capitalism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digitalization is such a reagent. The challenges it poses and the reactions it provokes open up a new field of research: the comparative political economy of digital capitalism. Drawing on the comparativist’s toolkit - developed in explaining earlier politico-economic transformations like globalization - much of my current work tries to explain when and why commodifying trends are reversed - for example by introducing ‘de-commodifying’ data protection or platform regulations; and to explain how disruptive changes are responded to - for example by investing in digital goods such as skills or R&amp;amp;D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gourevitch, P. (1977) ‘International Trade, Domestic Coalitions, and Liberty: Comparative Responses to the Crisis of 1873-1896’, The Journal of Interdisciplinary History, 8(2), p. 281. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas and Politics</title>
      <link>/projects/ideas-and-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/ideas-and-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More than a hundred years ago, Max Weber asked himself a question that still vexes the social scientists. How, he wondered, can ideas become &amp;ldquo;effective forces in history?&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; How can things like beliefs or narratives, visions of the futures or conjurations of the past change the ways in which people act and interact?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social scientists have long had a somewhat standoffish relationship with ideational explanations. During the cold war, the study of ideas sounded an awful lot like the study of ideology - an anathema for a new generation of self-confident social scientists who wanted to stay clear of the muddy waters of intellectual politics.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others believed that ideas are not explanatory variables in themselves but should be seen as “the product of circumstances and interests” or, at most, as “weapons framed for the furtherance of interests.&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Yet others thought that ideas may well matter, but they are simply too hard to measure. Ideas, as Philip Converse famously quipped, are a &amp;ldquo;primary exhibits for the doctrine that what is important to study cannot be measured and that what can be measured is not important to study.&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is, of course, rather curious “that scholars, whose entire existence is centered on the production and understanding of ideas, should grant ideas so little significance for explaining political life.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; But not only that. Why, one wonders, would businesses and politician channel so many resources into something that does not actually matter? And why would ordinary people spend so much time and energy defending and attacking things that are supposed to be &amp;lsquo;epiphenomenal&amp;rsquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The tens of millions of dollars that are spent on think tanks to churn out ideas and public relations firms to market them would be largely wasted. The billions of dollars spent on market research and on advertising would be unnecessary. (…) In politics, people would vote exclusively out of material self-interest. There would no longer be anything the matter with Kansas, and limousine liberals in Cambridge and Berkeley would become antitax crusaders. Job seekers would not choose careers because of their meaning; college students would stop trying to find themselves. Terrorists would not blow up buildings out of visions of religious glory or ideological triumph. There would be no such thing as a thought leader or a visionary.”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas, it should be clear, do matter, and it comes as no surprise that ideational explanations have experienced something of a comeback in recent years and decades. In my own research I build on the theoretical and empirical work done by these &amp;lsquo;scholars of the ideational renaissance&amp;rsquo;, who have managed to move the field from the question: do ideas matter? to: how and when do they matter? And: how can they be measured?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my own work, I explore how ideas can both change the ways in which actors perceive their own interests (and therefore their coalitional alignments), and how actors use ideas to advance their own interests by changing how others perceive theirs. But ideas, as the figure below illustrates, are not independent of the structural, ideational, and cultural context in which they operate. Rather actors’ interests are pre-shaped by their position in the political economy, and the power and plausibility of their interpretations of an always changing world depend on their fit with existing institutional regimes and other dominant ideas.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-ideas-and-institutions&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/Ideas_Interests.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ideas and Institutions&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/Ideas_Interests.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Ideas and Institutions
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weber, Max (2007): The Protestant Ethic and the Spirit of Capitalism. London: Routledge, p. 48. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geertz, Clifford (1964): Ideology as a Cultural System. In David E. Apter (Ed.): Ideology and Discontent. New York: The Free Press. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carr, Edward H. (2016 [1939]): The Twenty Years&amp;rsquo; Crisis, 1919-1939. Reissued with a New Preface from Michael Cox. London: Palgrave Macmillan UK, p. 65. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Converse, Philip E. (1964): The Nature of Belief Systems in Mass Publics. In David E. Apter (Ed.): Ideology and Discontent. New York: The Free Press, p. 206. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sikkink, Kathryn (1991): Ideas and institutions. Developmentalism in Brazil and Argentina. Ithaca: Cornell Univ. Press, p. 1. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mehta, Jal (2011): The Varied Roles of Ideas in Politics: From “Whether” to “How,”. In Daniel Béland, Robert Henry Cox (Eds.): Ideas and Politics in Social Science Research. Oxford: Oxford Univ. Press, p. 24. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text as Data</title>
      <link>/projects/text-as-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/text-as-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The flipside of my theoretical interest in the economic, social, and political role of ideas is my methodological interest in text as data approaches. Machine-readable texts have become widely available in recent years, and with them an impressive array of tools to make sense of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-uses-and-misuses-of-semantic-violence&#34;&gt;The uses and misuses of semantic violence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text as data approaches are characterized by a peculiar but instructive irony. As Kenneth Benoit observes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;generating insight from text as data is only possible once we have destroyed our ability to make sense of the texts directly. To make it useful as data, we had to obliterate the structure of the original text and turn its stylised and oversimplified features into a glorified spreadsheet that no reader can interpret directly, no matter how expert in linear algebra.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea that to do certain useful things with texts, we need to subject them to a certain amount of &amp;lsquo;semantic violence&amp;rsquo; goes to the heart of current debates on treating text as data. Text as data approaches are highly and often surprisingly useful tools: tools for &amp;lsquo;reading&amp;rsquo; or summarizing large amounts of text; tools for augmenting human abilities or reproducing human efforts; tools for discovering and measuring latent traits. But they also come at a cost - a cost that is usually worth paying for but that also needs to be taken account of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the cost that has to be paid - but also the potential price - seems roughly proportional to the amount of semantic violence being done to the texts. On one hand of the spectrum, word counts or perhaps simple keyword extraction techniques are quite intuitive, and can be interpreted relatively straightforwardly. They are, however, also more limited when it comes to scaling complex analyses or discovering sophisticated concepts. Topic models or machine learning methods, on the other hand, are much less intuitive and require much more careful validation. They can, however, also produce more interesting results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, awareness of such tradeoffs is a good starting point when thinking about how to do quantitative text analysis. Text as data approaches allows us to skip labor-intensive and often painful stages of the analysis, but they pose equally labor-intensive (and painful) challenges at other stages. While none of this is news, I periodically have to remind myself that treating text as data cannot and should not make my life as a researcher any easier - but, if done correctly, it can improve my research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-avenues&#34;&gt;Future Avenues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The field of text as data has seen such rapid progress in recent years that it becomes harder and harder to keep up. While I consider myself an informed consumer of the many methods and packages developed by this amazing community, I do have some thoughts on how to move things forward in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One promising avenue that is increasingly taken is integrate various text as data methods. This can mean using natural language processing for pre-processing (e.g. selecting parts of speech based on theoretical considerations); mutually validating different approaches by using them in combinations (e.g. dictionary-based approaches to validate topic models or topic models to &amp;lsquo;inspire&amp;rsquo; dictionaries); or using different approaches to answer nested questions (e.g. text networks to identify coalitions and scaling approaches to map them onto a latent dimension).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another angle, also increasingly used, is to combine text as data approaches with traditional methods, both quantitative and qualitative. This can mean using topic prevalence as a dependent or independent variable in regression models&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; to use survey experiments to establish causal links between topics identified in newspapers and public opinion&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; or to combine text as data methods with more interpretative approaches&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, to give just a few examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third approach is to think more systematically about the relationship between text as data approaches and social and political theory. This can mean methodologically reimagining important paradigms in the history of political thought&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; exploring affinities between text as data approaches and theories of culture&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; or using word embeddings to trace to test sociological theories about the cultural dimension of class.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A last approach that I would like to mention is to use text as data methods in a comparative setting. This has become much easier with the availability of relatively cheap but very reliable translation tools, which - in a text as data context - have been shown to yield results comparable to gold-standard human translations.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benoit, K. (2020) ‘Text as data: An Overview’, in Curini, L. and Franzese, R.J. (eds.) The SAGE handbook of research methods in political science and international relations. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barberá, P. et al. (2019) ‘Who Leads? Who Follows? Measuring Issue Attention and Agenda Setting by Legislators and the Mass Public Using Social Media Data’, American Political Science Review, 61, pp. 1–19. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barnes, L. and Hicks, T. (2018) ‘Making Austerity Popular: The Media and Mass Attitudes toward Fiscal Policy’, American Journal of Political Science, 62(2), pp. 340–354. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferrara, F.M. et al. (2018) ‘Exports vs. Investment: How Public Discourse Shapes Support for External Imbalances’. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nelson, L.K. (2017) ‘Computational Grounded Theory’, Sociological Methods &amp;amp; Research, 19, pp. 1-40. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;London, J.A. (2016) ‘Re-imagining the Cambridge School in the Age of Digital Humanities’, Annual Review of Political Science, 19(1), pp. 351–373. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bail, C.A. (2014) ‘The cultural environment: measuring culture with big data’, Theory and Society, 43(3-4), pp. 465–482. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DiMaggio, P., Nag, M. and Blei, D. (2013) ‘Exploiting affinities between topic modeling and the sociological perspective on culture: Application to newspaper coverage of U.S. government arts funding’, Poetics, 41(6), pp. 570–606. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kozlowski, A.C., Taddy, M. and Evans, J.A. (2019) ‘The Geometry of Culture: Analyzing the Meanings of Class through Word Embeddings’, American Sociological Review, 84(5), pp. 905–949. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vries, E. de, Schoonvelde, M. and Schumacher, G. (2018) ‘No Longer Lost in Translation: Evidence that Google Translate Works for Comparative Bag-of-Words Text Applications’, Political Analysis, 5, pp. 1–14. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proksch, S.-O., Wratil, C. and Wäckerle, J. (2019) ‘Testing the Validity of Automatic Speech Recognition for Political Text Analysis’, Political Analysis, 10, pp. 1–21. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytic Eclecticism, Nested Analysis</title>
      <link>/projects/mixing-methods-nesting-analyses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/mixing-methods-nesting-analyses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It sounds an awful lot like a cheap cliché, but I really am a believer in combining different analytical angles and empirical strategies to make a case. There are two dimensions to this: the eclectic utilization of concepts and mechanisms from different theoretical traditions, and the combination of different empirical methods such that one method builds upon and validates the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analytic-eclecticism&#34;&gt;Analytic Eclecticism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rudra Sil and Peter Katzenstein define analytic eclecticism as a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;intellectual stance that supports efforts to complement, engage, and selectively utilize theoretical constructs embedded in contending research traditions to build complex arguments that bear on substantive problems of interest to both scholars and practitioners.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conception - which strongly resonates with me - assumes a healthy division of labor between two social scientific camps (individual researchers can belong to both camps, even at the same time): first, there are the &amp;lsquo;normal scientists&amp;rsquo; that work in established research paradigms which define their questions and push them towards ever more elaborated and nuanced theories and empirical results; second, there are the analytical eclecticists which, as it were, parasitically utilize the conceptual and empirical knowledge accumulated in the paradigmatic sciences to answer questions that are defined less by a research tradition than by practical concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, normal scientists ask questions that mainly make sense in light of certain theoretical paradigms. In doing so, they accumulate ever more detailed knowledge about how the social world works. Analytic eclecticists ask questions that immediately make sense for practitioners or lay people as well, and they provide answers by synthetically combining concepts, causal mechanisms, or even methods from competing theoretical paradigms.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nested-analysis&#34;&gt;Nested Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evan Lieberman has proposed nested analysis as a mixed-method strategy for comparative and historical analyses as a way to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;assess the plausibility of observed statistical relationships between variables, to generate theoretical insights from outlier and other cases, and to develop better measurement strategies.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way of thinking about mixed method research remains highly relevant and serves as an encouragement to provide the best evidence available in order to answer a given question (which, alas, is often discouraged by the fast-moving realities of academic publishing). The methodological suggestions laid out in Lieberman&amp;rsquo;s articles provide a lodestar for the papers I would like to write but am not always able to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sil, R. and Katzenstein, P.J. (2010) ‘Analytic Eclecticism in the Study of World Politics: Reconfiguring Problems and Mechanisms across Research Traditions’, Perspectives on Politics, 8(2), pp. 411–431. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, there should probably be more &amp;lsquo;normal scientists&amp;rsquo; than analytic eclecticists but it sometimes feels like the career incentives in the social sciences have become overly skewed towards the former. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieberman, E.S. (2005) ‘Nested Analysis as a Mixed-Method Strategy for Comparative Research’, American Political Science Review, 99(3), pp. 435–452. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieberman, E.S. (2015) ‘Nested analysis: toward the integration of comparative-historical analysis with other social science methods’, in Mahoney, J. and Thelen, K.A. (eds.) Advances in comparative-historical analysis. Cambridge: Cambridge Univ. Press, pp. 240–263. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergence, Reductionism, Pragmatism?</title>
      <link>/projects/emergence-reductionism-pragmatism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/emergence-reductionism-pragmatism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a bit of an older strand of my work, and one that is at risk of losing itself in abstract theorizing. A while ago, I wrote a (somewhat turgid) chapter about my thinking on this topic, which hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed much since. Unfortunately (and naturally), however, it is in German, so here is a quick summary of my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, I find myself unconvinced by attempts to justify non-reductive forms of individualism.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; What do I mean by that? The central premise of non-reductive individualists is the &lt;em&gt;emergentist&lt;/em&gt; claim that while social phenomena must always be realized in individuals (much like thoughts must always be somehow realized in brain activity), they are nonetheless &lt;em&gt;irreducible&lt;/em&gt; to these underlying individual (or ultimately physical) processes in that they exert independent causal influences on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going into too much detail here, it strikes me as implausible that things that are always realized on a lower level can also be somehow independent of these lower levels (this is the same criticism that Jaegwon Kim&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; has levelled against analogous arguments in the philosophy of mind). If everything always also has to happen on the lower level, there is simply nothing left to do for top-down causality. Either things happen on a higher level that don&amp;rsquo;t happen on a lower level, or there is no causal work left to do for higher-level processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going further down this rabbit hole, we find ourselves at an impasse. What seems obvious, namely that psychology or biology, not to speak of physics, don&amp;rsquo;t even come close to offering a reasonable explanation for the intricacies and eccentricities of social and political life, also seems philosophically questionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is of course resolved if we acknowledge that the language game social scientists play offers incredibly useful &lt;em&gt;shortcuts&lt;/em&gt; for describing processes that would be devilishly difficult to describe otherwise (it is, after all, also much easier to say &amp;ldquo;I am hungry&amp;rdquo; than to give an detailed account of the complex physiological processes that underlie both the feeling of hunger and its representation in the mind).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if that is the case, why even bother with psychological or biological explanations? Why not just keep playing the social scientific language game if that gets us where we want to be? Well, it is not that easy either. That is because if we acknowledge that all social life is realized in individuals - that causality flows only between individuals and not from society &amp;ldquo;down&amp;rdquo; to individuals - we also need to acknowledge that our theories of social life should not contradict the best theories we have about individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But fear not, fellow social scientists. In the pragmatist understanding I offer, the social sciences are not reduced to a biologistic or psychologistic science of the individual, but need only be &lt;em&gt;compatible&lt;/em&gt; with their findings. This is not to say, of course, that social scientists cannot challenge these findings, but they should seriously engage with those that are well replicated and adjust their theories accordingly (for an excellent example, see Stephen Vaisey&amp;rsquo;s work on sociological theories of motivation and justification&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is in this spirit that I made the case for a more serious and sustained engagement between &amp;ldquo;human scientists&amp;rdquo; from different backgrounds. It heartening to see that multiple lines of research converge on similar conclusions, from the work on the social-evolutionary origins of human thinking and human morality&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, to the work at the intersection of sociology and genetics&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, to the &amp;ldquo;social turn&amp;rdquo; in many life sciences&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, to the &amp;ldquo;psychological turn&amp;rdquo; in many subfields of political science.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no current projects in this area, but I am convinced that a full account of social life needs to take recourse to not only structural, institutional, and ideational explanations, but also to psychological (or biological) ones - sometimes this simply mean to make sure that our theories do not outrightly contradict &amp;ldquo;lower-level&amp;rdquo; theories, sometimes it means to actively incorporate (and advance) them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greve, J. (2012) ‘Emergence in Sociology: A Critique of Nonreductive Individualism’, Philosophy of the Social Sciences, 42(2), pp. 188–223. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kim, J. (ed.) (1993) Supervenience and mind: Selected philosophical essays. New York: Cambridge University Press. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaisey, S. (2009) ‘Motivation and Justification: A Dual-Process Model of Culture in Action’, American Journal of Sociology, 114(6), pp. 1675–1715. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomasello, M. (2014) A Natural History of Human Thinking. Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard Univ. Press.
Tomasello, M. (2016) A Natural History of Human Morality. Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard University Press. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freese, J. and Shostak, S. (2009) ‘Genetics and Social Inquiry’, Annual Review of Sociology, 35(1), pp. 107–128. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meloni, M. (2014) ‘How biology became social, and what it means for social theory’, The Sociological Review, 62(3), pp. 593–614. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Kertzer, J.D. and Tingley, D. (2018) ‘Political Psychology in International Relations: Beyond the Paradigms’, Annual Review of Political Science, 21(1), pp. 319–339. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Science and Social Criticism?</title>
      <link>/projects/social-science-and-social-criticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/social-science-and-social-criticism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is perhaps the &lt;em&gt;Gretchenfrage&lt;/em&gt; for every social scientist: &amp;ldquo;how do you feel about social criticism?&amp;rdquo; My own thinking on this question is formed by three attempts to find an answer which can live up to the gravity of the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-frankfurt-school-and-the-search-for-a-yardstick&#34;&gt;The Frankfurt School and the search for a yardstick&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have long been fascinated by attempts to develop a normative yardstick by which to judge whether a particular social practice or arrangement is good or bad, worthy of critic or deserving of respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a certain sense, these attempts to put social criticism on an &amp;lsquo;objective&amp;rsquo; normative foundation failed, and were perhaps doomed to fail. But they also produced a rich body of work at the intersection of social philosophy and empirical social science that I continue to feel drawn to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social philosophers of the Frankfurt School were among the first to insist on the connection between normative theorizing and empirical work. In looking at modern societies from this meta-theoretical vantage point, some of its members came to express an intuition that has always rung true to me: that despite its flaws, modernity (as an empirical phenomenon) is something (normatively) worth saving. Foremost among these thinkers is Jürgen Habermas. Habermas&amp;rsquo; theory of communicative action is an attempt to conceive of modernization as a deeply ambivalent process - a process that has released the search for truth, justice, and beauty from their traditional shackles while also untethering the capitalist from its societal bounds.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Habermas, the critic is called upon when the logic of systemic imperatives - the ruthless search for profit or the unjustified exercise of administrative power - distorts and subjugates the communicative logic of the lifeworld. It would mean doing injustice to the considerable &lt;em&gt;sociological&lt;/em&gt; complexity of Habermas&amp;rsquo; theory to accuse him of empirical naivety. Habermas did of course not think that the lifeworld was free of power relations, even in the absence of encroaching systemic imperatives. But I always thought the major flaw in his theory was that it lacks a concept of &amp;lsquo;symbolic&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;noumenal power&amp;rsquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; - of a power that affects the communicative taking and making of arguments itself, i.e., what people accept as &amp;lsquo;good reasons&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;foucault-and-the-apotheosis-of-subversion&#34;&gt;Foucault and the apotheosis of subversion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is problem is in a way the starting point for a second strand of social criticism. From Friedrich Nietzsche to Michel Foucault, these genealogical critics have attempt to drill holes in the solid concrete of the everyday lifeworld by asking its inhabitants to look in the mirror of their own, often dark and always contingent collective histories.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The point of these genealogical critics, as Foucault readily acknowledges, is no longer to put criticism on normative foundation, but to elicit a &amp;ldquo;limit-experience&amp;rdquo; that &amp;ldquo;changes us, that prevents us from always being the same, or from having the same kind of relationship with things and others that we had before.&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
But this creates a problem: what is the point of eliciting such limit-experiences if there is no normative foundation from which to judge the relative quality of a given norm, practice, or social order? With no place left to stand on, the critic can only resort to celebrating the notion of subversion itself. Foucault says he does what he does so that those implicated in relations of power&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;might escape them through their actions of resistance and rebellion, might transform them in order not to be subjugated any longer. And if I don&amp;rsquo;t ever say what must be done, it isn&amp;rsquo;t because I believe that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing to be done; on the contrary, it is because I think that there are a thousand things to do, to invent, to forge, on the part of those who, recognizing the relations of power in which they&amp;rsquo;re implicated, have decided to resist or escape them. From this point of view all of my investigations rest on a postulate of absolute optimism. I do not conduct my analyses in order to say: this is how things are, look how trapped you are. I say certain things only to the extent to which I see them as capable of permitting the transformation of reality.&amp;quot;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why subversion - and the &amp;ldquo;limit-experience&amp;rdquo; it elicits - is better than compliance is not - and cannot be - answered. If everything solid melts into air, we can only hope to land softly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bourdieu-and-the-freedom-in-determinism&#34;&gt;Bourdieu and the freedom in determinism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third strand of social criticism, most eloquently developed by Pierre Bourdieu, has maneuvered itself into a similar cul-de-sac. For Bourdieu, social criticism is deeply entangled with questions of social determinism. In his sociological work, he had demonstrated the structuring effects of social fields and social power. For Bourdieu, communicative action was always distorted by the pernicious logic of symbolic power - the power that makes the dominated accept and internalize the reasons for their domination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for Bourdieu there was a way out, at least sort of. For Bourdieu, and here he agreed with Foucault, there was no going back behind the knowledge and acknowledgment of our own historicity - the fact that who we are and what we believe, as individuals and societies, is profoundly shaped by social and historical forces. But this, Bourdieu insisted, does not mean abandoning the possibility of criticism but rather radicalizing it by asking about the social conditions of its possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In short, it is only through recognizing one&amp;rsquo;s historicity that it becomes possible for Reason to extricate itself from it&amp;rdquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Bourdieu means here is that we can only think of escaping our historicity - the ways in which history and society shape us - if we understand and acknowledge it, much like we could only build airplanes after we understood and acknowledged the laws of gravity. Freedom, then, does not disappear in the face of determinism but requires us to recognize it. But, Bourdieu realizes, our ability to uncover the laws that govern social life is itself a product of history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I tend to pose the question regarding reason, or norms in a radically historical way. My initial question would be: in whose interest is universalism? or what are the social conditions in which certain actors come to be interested in it? (&amp;hellip;) This historicism has to be pushed to its limits through radical doubt in order to see what can still be saved &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Bourdieu, science itself is the product of contingent (and reversible) historical circumstances that have established a situation in which all actors have an interest in finding the truth - as opposed to politically convenient, economically lucrative, or morally comfortable lies. This is why science is so important; it carves out a socially constructed space for people to pursue the truth - and to get something out of it. Only under these conditions - however imperfect they may be - can we hope to understand and therefore at least somewhat escape - the iron laws of determinism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-social-critic-as-a-gardener&#34;&gt;The social critic as a gardener&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is here that my thinking on social criticism has arrived - at least for the moment. We, as (social) scientists are the privileged children of modernity which has put us in a position to be able to play a game in which we can win by pursuing the truth, at least in principle. And in doing so, we can provide individuals and societies with the knowledge to understand and accept their own complicity in historically grown and socially structured power relations. And it is this knowledge that they need to make - in acts of communicative interaction - decisions about their individual and collective fate that have at least the semblance of freedom. For me, then, the job of the social critic is much like the job of the gardener: to remove the weed of false freedom - freedom ignorant of its determination - in order to give the delicate flower of true freedom - freedom educated about its own determination - a chance to blossom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Habermas, J. (1987) The Theory of Communicative Action: Volume 2. Lifeworld and System: A Critique of Functionalist Reason. Boston: Beacon. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forst, R. (2017) ‘Noumenal Power’, in Forst, R. (ed.) Normativity and Power: Analyzing Social Orders of Justification. Oxford: Oxford University Press, pp.37–51. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foucault, M. (1984) ‘What is Enlightenment?’ in Rabinow, P. (ed.) The Foucault Reader. New York: Vintage Books, pp. 32–50. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foucault, M. (1991) Remarks on Marx: Conversations with Duccio Trombardori: Semiotext(e). &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honneth, A., Kocyba, H. and Schwibs, B. (1986) ‘The Struggle for Symbolic Order an Interview with Pierre Bourdieu’, Theory, Culture &amp;amp; Society, 3(3), p. 46. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honneth, A., Kocyba, H. and Schwibs, B. (1986) ‘The Struggle for Symbolic Order an Interview with Pierre Bourdieu’, Theory, Culture &amp;amp; Society, 3(3), p. 48. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Moral Embeddedness of Economic Action</title>
      <link>/projects/moral-embeddness-of-economic-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/moral-embeddness-of-economic-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the central tenets of economic sociology is that economic life - even in capitalist societies - is always embedded in non-economic life, be it the trust-generating social networks that grease the wheels of markets, the &amp;lsquo;reproductive&amp;rsquo; work in families that makes &amp;lsquo;productive&amp;rsquo; work possible, or the moral economies that justify the &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; ones. It is this later phenomenon, the essential and continuing moral contestedness of capitalism, and the pervasiveness of (stymied) moral impulses in capitalist life that have aroused my interest in the moral embeddedness of economic action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-spirit-of-capitalism&#34;&gt;The Spirit of Capitalism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my empirical work, I have used the concept of the spirit of capitalism to make sense of the ways in which normative ideas motivate, legitimize, and orient the actions of capitalist actors. Drawing on a long tradition of scholarship that ranges from Sombart to Weber to Boltanski and Chiapello, I have tried to think more empirically about both, the overt strategic uses of morality, and the more subtle ways in which moral ideas influence strategic calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about my thinking on the capitalist spirit in my paper(s) on the spirit of capitalism; and you can read more about my thinking about the relationship between capitalism and morality in my (overly lengthy and learned) master thesis, which you can download 
&lt;a href=&#34;Moral_Embeddedness.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>German Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>/projects/german-foreign-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/german-foreign-policy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an undergraduate, I became quite interested in the drivers of Germany&amp;rsquo;s foreign policy. And while I no longer actively pursue this question, some of the underlying concerns remain very close to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;state-identities&#34;&gt;State identities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, I remain fascinated by what constitutes and defines a state&amp;rsquo;s identity. In my own work, I found surprisingly deep ideational and organizational continuities in German foreign policy – continuities that out-lived partisan changes. I also found that ideas - from a default ordoliberal view of the economy, to a vaguely felt obligation to the German national interest, to the widely shared believe that Germany is, by and large, a force for good in the world - to be important drivers of foreign policy decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more recent work, I take up this question of state identity in the context of economic and fiscal policymaking. How, for example, does the way states understand themselves and their role in the economy influence their spending decisions?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; How do their views on the virtues of debt shape their views of the relative merits of savings and investments?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-geopolitics-of-political-economy&#34;&gt;The geopolitics of political economy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way in which my thinking on German foreign policy continues to inform my current work is by making me take the geopolitical dimension of politico-economic phenomena seriously. Especially in a world of &amp;lsquo;weaponized interdependence&amp;rsquo;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, geopolitics and the politics of economic and public policymaking are inextricably intertwined. Geopolitical concerns are crucial for innovation and innovation policy&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;; questions of internet governance are increasingly complicated by the geopolitical competition between different visions and versions of the internet; and, as I showed in my own work on Germany&amp;rsquo;s response to the euro crisis, seemingly economic decisions are in fact motivated by geopolitical ambitions as much as by economic interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mazzucato, M. (2013) The Entrepreneurial State: Debunking Public vs. Private Sector Myths. London: Anthem Press. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dyson, K.H.F. (2014) States, Debt, and Power: &amp;ldquo;Saints&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Sinners&amp;rdquo; in European History and Integration. Oxford: Oxford Univ. Press. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farrell, H. and Newman, A.L. (2019) ‘Weaponized Interdependence: How Global Economic Networks Shape State Coercion’, International Security, 44(1), pp. 42–79. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weiss, L.M. (2014) America inc.? Innovation and enterprise in the national security state. Ithaca, NY: Cornell University Press. &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talkin’ bout Digitalization</title>
      <link>/publication/talkin-about-digitalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/talkin-about-digitalization/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the European Data-Driven Economy. A Case Study on the General Data Protection Regulation</title>
      <link>/publication/regulating-the-european-data-driven-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/regulating-the-european-data-driven-economy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Politics of Platform Capitalism. A Case Study on the Regulation of Uber in New York</title>
      <link>/publication/the-politics-of-platform-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/the-politics-of-platform-capitalism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Techlash in Times of Corona</title>
      <link>/publication/techlash-in-times-of-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/techlash-in-times-of-corona/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit of Digital Capitalism</title>
      <link>/publication/spirit-of-digital-capitalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/spirit-of-digital-capitalism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review, Appadurai, Arjun. and Alexander, Neta (2020) Failure, Cambridge. Polity Press</title>
      <link>/publication/book-review-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/book-review-failure/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideologie und der Geist des digitalen Kapitalismus</title>
      <link>/publication/ideologie-und-ethik-der-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ideologie-und-ethik-der-solution/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing technical content in Academic</title>
      <link>/post/writing-technical-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/writing-technical-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Academic is designed to give technical content creators a seamless experience. You can focus on the content and Academic handles the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlight your code snippets, take notes on math classes, and draw diagrams from textual representation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this page, you&amp;rsquo;ll find some examples of the types of technical content that can be rendered with Academic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic supports a Markdown extension for highlighting code syntax. You can enable this feature by toggling the &lt;code&gt;highlight&lt;/code&gt; option in your &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.toml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```python
import pandas as pd
data = pd.read_csv(&amp;quot;data.csv&amp;quot;)
data.head()
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import pandas as pd
data = pd.read_csv(&amp;quot;data.csv&amp;quot;)
data.head()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic supports a Markdown extension for $\LaTeX$ math. You can enable this feature by toggling the &lt;code&gt;math&lt;/code&gt; option in your &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.toml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To render &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; math, wrap your LaTeX math with &lt;code&gt;$...$&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;$$...$$&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;math block&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-tex&#34;&gt;$$\gamma_{n} = \frac{ 
\left | \left (\mathbf x_{n} - \mathbf x_{n-1} \right )^T 
\left [\nabla F (\mathbf x_{n}) - \nabla F (\mathbf x_{n-1}) \right ] \right |}
{\left \|\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n}) - \nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n-1}) \right \|^2}$$
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$\gamma_{n} = \frac{ \left | \left (\mathbf x_{n} - \mathbf x_{n-1} \right )^T \left [\nabla F (\mathbf x_{n}) - \nabla F (\mathbf x_{n-1}) \right ] \right |}{\left |\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n}) - \nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n-1}) \right |^2}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;inline math&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;$\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})$&lt;/code&gt; renders as $\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;multi-line math&lt;/strong&gt; using the &lt;code&gt;\\&lt;/code&gt; math linebreak:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-tex&#34;&gt;$$f(k;p_0^*) = \begin{cases} p_0^* &amp;amp; \text{if }k=1, \\
1-p_0^* &amp;amp; \text {if }k=0.\end{cases}$$
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$f(k;p_0^*) = \begin{cases} p_0^* &amp;amp; \text{if }k=1, \&lt;br&gt;
1-p_0^* &amp;amp; \text {if }k=0.\end{cases}$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;diagrams&#34;&gt;Diagrams&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic supports a Markdown extension for diagrams. You can enable this feature by toggling the &lt;code&gt;diagram&lt;/code&gt; option in your &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.toml&lt;/code&gt; file or by adding &lt;code&gt;diagram: true&lt;/code&gt; to your page front matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;flowchart&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
graph TD
A[Hard] --&amp;gt;|Text| B(Round)
B --&amp;gt; C{Decision}
C --&amp;gt;|One| D[Result 1]
C --&amp;gt;|Two| E[Result 2]
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;graph TD
A[Hard] --&amp;gt;|Text| B(Round)
B --&amp;gt; C{Decision}
C --&amp;gt;|One| D[Result 1]
C --&amp;gt;|Two| E[Result 2]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;sequence diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
sequenceDiagram
Alice-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Hello John, how are you?
loop Healthcheck
    John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Fight against hypochondria
end
Note right of John: Rational thoughts!
John--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Alice: Great!
John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Bob: How about you?
Bob--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Jolly good!
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;sequenceDiagram
Alice-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Hello John, how are you?
loop Healthcheck
    John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Fight against hypochondria
end
Note right of John: Rational thoughts!
John--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Alice: Great!
John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Bob: How about you?
Bob--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Jolly good!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;Gantt diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
gantt
section Section
Completed :done,    des1, 2014-01-06,2014-01-08
Active        :active,  des2, 2014-01-07, 3d
Parallel 1   :         des3, after des1, 1d
Parallel 2   :         des4, after des1, 1d
Parallel 3   :         des5, after des3, 1d
Parallel 4   :         des6, after des4, 1d
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;gantt
section Section
Completed :done,    des1, 2014-01-06,2014-01-08
Active        :active,  des2, 2014-01-07, 3d
Parallel 1   :         des3, after des1, 1d
Parallel 2   :         des4, after des1, 1d
Parallel 3   :         des5, after des3, 1d
Parallel 4   :         des6, after des4, 1d
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;class diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
classDiagram
Class01 &amp;lt;|-- AveryLongClass : Cool
&amp;lt;&amp;lt;interface&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Class01
Class09 --&amp;gt; C2 : Where am i?
Class09 --* C3
Class09 --|&amp;gt; Class07
Class07 : equals()
Class07 : Object[] elementData
Class01 : size()
Class01 : int chimp
Class01 : int gorilla
class Class10 {
  &amp;lt;&amp;lt;service&amp;gt;&amp;gt;
  int id
  size()
}
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;classDiagram
Class01 &amp;lt;|-- AveryLongClass : Cool
&amp;lt;&amp;lt;interface&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Class01
Class09 --&amp;gt; C2 : Where am i?
Class09 --* C3
Class09 --|&amp;gt; Class07
Class07 : equals()
Class07 : Object[] elementData
Class01 : size()
Class01 : int chimp
Class01 : int gorilla
class Class10 {
  &amp;lt;&amp;lt;service&amp;gt;&amp;gt;
  int id
  size()
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;state diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
stateDiagram
[*] --&amp;gt; Still
Still --&amp;gt; [*]
Still --&amp;gt; Moving
Moving --&amp;gt; Still
Moving --&amp;gt; Crash
Crash --&amp;gt; [*]
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;stateDiagram
[*] --&amp;gt; Still
Still --&amp;gt; [*]
Still --&amp;gt; Moving
Moving --&amp;gt; Still
Moving --&amp;gt; Crash
Crash --&amp;gt; [*]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;todo-lists&#34;&gt;Todo lists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can even write your todo lists in Academic too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;- [x] Write math example
- [x] Write diagram example
- [ ] Do something else
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Write math example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Write diagram example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Do something else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tables&#34;&gt;Tables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Represent your data in tables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;| First Header  | Second Header |
| ------------- | ------------- |
| Content Cell  | Content Cell  |
| Content Cell  | Content Cell  |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;First Header&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Second Header&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Content Cell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Content Cell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Content Cell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Content Cell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;asides&#34;&gt;Asides&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic supports a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/#alerts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcode for asides&lt;/a&gt;, also referred to as &lt;em&gt;notices&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;hints&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;alerts&lt;/em&gt;. By wrapping a paragraph in &lt;code&gt;{{% alert note %}} ... {{% /alert %}}&lt;/code&gt;, it will render as an aside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% alert note %}}
A Markdown aside is useful for displaying notices, hints, or definitions to your readers.
{{% /alert %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    A Markdown aside is useful for displaying notices, hints, or definitions to your readers.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;icons&#34;&gt;Icons&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic enables you to use a wide range of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/page-builder/#icons&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;icons from &lt;em&gt;Font Awesome&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Academicons&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in addition to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/#emojis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;emojis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples using the &lt;code&gt;icon&lt;/code&gt; shortcode to render icons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; icon name=&amp;quot;terminal&amp;quot; pack=&amp;quot;fas&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}} Terminal  
{{&amp;lt; icon name=&amp;quot;python&amp;quot; pack=&amp;quot;fab&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}} Python  
{{&amp;lt; icon name=&amp;quot;r-project&amp;quot; pack=&amp;quot;fab&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}} R
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-terminal  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Terminal&lt;br&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-python  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Python&lt;br&gt;

  &lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-r-project  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; R&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display Jupyter Notebooks with Academic</title>
      <link>/post/jupyter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/jupyter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;from IPython.core.display import Image
Image(&#39;https://www.python.org/static/community_logos/python-logo-master-v3-TM-flattened.png&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./index_1_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;print(&amp;quot;Welcome to Academic!&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Welcome to Academic!
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-python-and-jupyterlab&#34;&gt;Install Python and JupyterLab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anaconda.com/distribution/#download-section&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Install Anaconda&lt;/a&gt; which includes Python 3 and JupyterLab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, install JupyterLab with &lt;code&gt;pip3 install jupyterlab&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-or-upload-a-jupyter-notebook&#34;&gt;Create or upload a Jupyter notebook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run the following commands in your Terminal, substituting &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;MY-WEBSITE-FOLDER&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;SHORT-POST-TITLE&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; with the file path to your Academic website folder and a short title for your blog post (use hyphens instead of spaces), respectively:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;mkdir -p &amp;lt;MY-WEBSITE-FOLDER&amp;gt;/content/post/&amp;lt;SHORT-POST-TITLE&amp;gt;/
cd &amp;lt;MY-WEBSITE-FOLDER&amp;gt;/content/post/&amp;lt;SHORT-POST-TITLE&amp;gt;/
jupyter lab index.ipynb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;jupyter&lt;/code&gt; command above will launch the JupyterLab editor, allowing us to add Academic metadata and write the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;edit-your-post-metadata&#34;&gt;Edit your post metadata&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first cell of your Jupter notebook will contain your post metadata (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/front-matter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;front matter&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Jupter, choose &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; as the type of the first cell and wrap your Academic metadata in three dashes, indicating that it is YAML front matter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
title: My post&#39;s title
date: 2019-09-01

# Put any other Academic metadata here...
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit the metadata of your post, using the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; as a guide to the available options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#featured-image&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;featured image&lt;/a&gt;, place an image named &lt;code&gt;featured&lt;/code&gt; into your post&amp;rsquo;s folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other tips, such as using math, see the guide on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;writing content with Academic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;convert-notebook-to-markdown&#34;&gt;Convert notebook to Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;jupyter nbconvert index.ipynb --to markdown --NbConvertApp.output_files_dir=.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;example&#34;&gt;Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was created with Jupyter. The orginal files can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite/content/post/jupyter&#34;&gt;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite/content/post/jupyter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die Linke und der Geist des digitalen Kapitalismus</title>
      <link>/publication/die-linke-und-der-geist-des-digitalen-kapitalismus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/die-linke-und-der-geist-des-digitalen-kapitalismus/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Die Ethik der Solution und der Geist des digitalen Kapitalismus</title>
      <link>/publication/ethik-der-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/ethik-der-solution/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kompatibilität statt Reduktion. Zur Idee einer Interdisziplinären Anthropologie als soziologischem Selbst- und Fremdver(un)sicherungsraum</title>
      <link>/publication/kompatibilitat-statt-reduktion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/kompatibilitat-statt-reduktion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Das doppelte Ziel der deutschen Eurokrisenpolitik</title>
      <link>/publication/eine-stabilitaes-und-wettbewerbsunion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/eine-stabilitaes-und-wettbewerbsunion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website builder for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a free website with Academic using Markdown, Jupyter, or RStudio. Choose a beautiful color theme and build anything with the Page Builder - over 40 &lt;em&gt;widgets&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;themes&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;language packs&lt;/em&gt; included!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out the latest &lt;strong&gt;demo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/#expo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;view the &lt;strong&gt;showcase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of personal, project, and business sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 
&lt;a href=&#34;#install&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get Started&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;View the &lt;strong&gt;documentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💬 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask a question&lt;/strong&gt; on the forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👥 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://spectrum.chat/academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chat with the &lt;strong&gt;community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐦 Twitter: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/source_themes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@source_themes&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@GeorgeCushen&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23MadeWithAcademic&amp;amp;src=typd&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#MadeWithAcademic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💡 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Request a &lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt; or report a &lt;strong&gt;bug&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⬆️ &lt;strong&gt;Updating?&lt;/strong&gt; View the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;❤️ &lt;strong&gt;Support development&lt;/strong&gt; of Academic:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;☕️ 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donate a coffee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💵 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/cushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Become a backer on &lt;strong&gt;Patreon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🖼️ 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redbubble.com/people/neutreno/works/34387919-academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Decorate your laptop or journal with an Academic &lt;strong&gt;sticker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👕 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.threadless.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wear the &lt;strong&gt;T-shirt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👩‍💻 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/contribute/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribute&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-academic-is-mobile-first-with-a-responsive-design-to-ensure-that-your-site-looks-stunning-on-every-device&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;Academic is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Academic is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/themes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 15+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic comes with &lt;strong&gt;automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Alternatively, visitors can  choose their preferred mode - click the sun/moon icon in the top right of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt; to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in &lt;code&gt;params.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/themes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Choose a stunning &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for your site. Themes are fully 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/customization/#custom-theme&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;customizable&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-admin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic Admin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An admin tool to import publications from BibTeX or import assets for an offline site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-scripts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic Scripts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Scripts to help migrate content to new versions of Academic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-web-browser&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-git&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;install on your computer using &lt;strong&gt;Git&lt;/strong&gt; with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;install on your computer by downloading the &lt;strong&gt;ZIP files&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;install on your computer with &lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/get-started/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;personalize and deploy your new site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;View the Update Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;updates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;r-markdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can embed an R code chunk like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;summary(cars)
##      speed           dist       
##  Min.   : 4.0   Min.   :  2.00  
##  1st Qu.:12.0   1st Qu.: 26.00  
##  Median :15.0   Median : 36.00  
##  Mean   :15.4   Mean   : 42.98  
##  3rd Qu.:19.0   3rd Qu.: 56.00  
##  Max.   :25.0   Max.   :120.00
fit &amp;lt;- lm(dist ~ speed, data = cars)
fit
## 
## Call:
## lm(formula = dist ~ speed, data = cars)
## 
## Coefficients:
## (Intercept)        speed  
##     -17.579        3.932&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;including-plots&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Including Plots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also embed plots. See Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:pie&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;par(mar = c(0, 1, 0, 1))
pie(
  c(280, 60, 20),
  c(&amp;#39;Sky&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sunny side of pyramid&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Shady side of pyramid&amp;#39;),
  col = c(&amp;#39;#0292D8&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#F7EA39&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#C4B632&amp;#39;),
  init.angle = -50, border = NA
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:pie&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown_files/figure-html/pie-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A fancy pie chart.&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: A fancy pie chart.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to Call Things as They are</title>
      <link>/publication/time-to-call-things-as-they-are/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/time-to-call-things-as-they-are/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Im »Südwesten« nichts Neues? Eine Analyse der deutschen Namibiapolitik als Beitrag zur Rekonstruktion der außenpolitischen Identität des deutschen Nationalstaates</title>
      <link>/publication/im-suedwesten-nichts-neues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/im-suedwesten-nichts-neues/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Das doppelte Ziel der deutschen Eurokrisenpolitik</title>
      <link>/publication/das-doppelte-ziel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/das-doppelte-ziel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Comparative Political Economy</title>
      <link>/courses/introduction-to-comparative-political-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/courses/introduction-to-comparative-political-economy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
